<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Emerson MX</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Emerson MX</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 16:30:11 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.emersonmx.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skelly: A Scaffold Tool</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/skelly-a-scaffold-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 16:30:11 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/skelly-a-scaffold-tool/</guid><description>I've been facing issues with scaffold tools for a long time, whether because they’re slow or missing essential features. But one day, I got tired of these limitations and decided to create my own tool 😁.
I chose a trendy language (Rust) and started looking for libraries that could help me implement what I had in mind. I wanted something easy to install, with a template engine similar to Jinja2, that could work with pipes and offer only the essentials.</description></item><item><title>Tic Tac Toe</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/policies/tictactoe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 12:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/policies/tictactoe/</guid><description>Privacy Policy Introduction Welcome to TicTacToe! This Privacy Policy is designed to inform you about how we handle your data when you use our Android application (&amp;quot;App&amp;quot;). We value your privacy and want to ensure you that your information is safe with us.
No Data Collection We do not collect, store, or process any personal data or information from users of the TicTacToe app.
Children's Privacy TicTacToe is suitable for users of all ages.</description></item><item><title>Starting a Python "project"</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/starting-a-python-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/starting-a-python-project/</guid><description>Lately, I've been creating a lot of cookiecutter templates to use in my throwaway projects. I even created a script (cocu) to simplify the process, but I rarely remember to use it. During this period, I struggled a lot with the cookiecutter, but in the end, I came to the conclusion that it is simpler to document the process of creating a new project than to blindly depend on it.</description></item><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:12:58 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hello world! :D</description></item></channel></rss>