<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Emerson MX</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Emerson MX</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:19:07 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rediscovering C: Finding Excitement Beyond the Usual Tech Content</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/rediscovering-c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:19:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/rediscovering-c/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve found myself running out of topics that genuinely interest me when
it comes to software architecture, infrastructure, and related areas. Most of
the content I come across feels repetitive and doesn’t add much value—it’s
often the same ideas being recycled in different words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having studied C during my time at university, I decided to dive deeper
into the language. I believe that low-level knowledge is essential for any
developer, and C offers a unique perspective that higher-level languages often
abstract away.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simple Server with libuv</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/simple-server-libuv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 11:37:17 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/simple-server-libuv/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for a simple, modern C server to tinker with? This sample project is a
minimal HTTP server built using &lt;a href="https://libuv.org/"&gt;libuv&lt;/a&gt;, the same
high-performance event library that powers Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why libuv? It lets you write asynchronous, cross-platform network code in C
without the headaches of manual event loops or platform-specific APIs. This
server listens for HTTP requests, responds with a friendly message, and
gracefully shuts down when you hit Ctrl+C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is intentionally compact—just enough to show how to accept
connections, read requests, and send responses. If you’re curious about how
event-driven servers work under the hood, this is a great starting point.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introducing tp: Effortless Tmux Session Management</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/introducing-tp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/introducing-tp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Managing &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; sessions can sometimes involve a repetitive dance of
&lt;code&gt;new-session&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;new-window&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;split-window&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;send-keys&lt;/code&gt; commands. While
powerful, this manual setup can become cumbersome, especially for complex
project layouts or when you need to quickly spin up a consistent development
environment across different machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;code&gt;tp&lt;/code&gt; comes in. Inspired by the desire for a simpler, more
declarative way to handle &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; sessions, &lt;code&gt;tp&lt;/code&gt; is a command-line tool written
in Rust designed to streamline this process. It allows you to define your
entire &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; session, including multiple windows and panes with specific
directories and commands, in simple YAML configuration files, and then load
them with a single command.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Difficulties in Building a Pygame Game for Android</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/difficulties-in-building-a-pygame-game-for-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 17:03:25 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/difficulties-in-building-a-pygame-game-for-android/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was taking an &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/courses"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; course and got the urge to port a game I
had made in &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; to Android. It wasn't difficult to find articles on the
subject, but one common theme was that to run Python on Android, you needed
&lt;a href="https://github.com/kivy/buildozer"&gt;Buildozer&lt;/a&gt;. And so, my saga began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent two days wrestling with Buildozer to generate an APK. On the first day,
I decided to create a simple example to test the build. After encountering
several errors, I realized it would be easier to run Buildozer in &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;.
Luckily, there was already a Dockerfile in the Buildozer project for this
purpose. With a few adaptations, I had it up and running on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skelly: A Scaffold Tool</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/skelly-a-scaffold-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 16:30:11 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/skelly-a-scaffold-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been facing issues with scaffold tools for a long time, whether because
they’re slow or missing essential features. But one day, I got tired of these
limitations and decided to create my own tool 😁.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose a trendy language (&lt;a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/"&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;) and started looking for libraries that could
help me implement what I had in mind. I wanted something easy to install, with
a template engine similar to &lt;a href="https://jinja.palletsprojects.com/en/2.10.x/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt;, that could work with pipes and offer
only the essentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Starting a Python "project"</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/starting-a-python-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/starting-a-python-project/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I've been creating a lot of &lt;a href="https://github.com/emersonmx/cookiecutters"&gt;cookiecutter templates&lt;/a&gt; to use in my
throwaway projects. I even created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/emersonmx/dotfiles/blob/main/dot_local/bin/executable_cocu"&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;code&gt;cocu&lt;/code&gt;) to simplify the
process, but I rarely remember to use it. During this period, I struggled a
lot with the &lt;code&gt;cookiecutter&lt;/code&gt;, but in the end, I came to the conclusion that it
is simpler to document the process of creating a new project than to blindly
depend on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process I'm following is quite simple; just follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:12:58 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.emersonmx.dev/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hello world! :D&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>